hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
the obstacles let's look at our next
obstacle which is uh again a dynamic
date generation so in this particular
obstacle we need to input tomorrow's
date in that particular text box so what
do you mean by tomorrow's datee is
whatever date is today and then you need
to add another day uh to today's date
and then you need to enter that
accordingly so as you know uh the date
would be dynamically generated otherwise
uh the dates could be a problem if you
execute it on different days right so
let's see how we can do this uh in
tosa so coming back here I am going to
add the module here we just need the
text box here
right so I'm going to scan this
application and then I'm going to add
the date field okay so I'm going to
rename this
also and also we will rename the
module okay and then I'm going to save
this and close
this okay so now coming back to tosa and
in test cases we will go to
obstacles and we'll create our new
obstacle
here and then uh we are going to add the
module
here okay so now we have to use the
dynamic expression uh for date to
generate tomorrow's date okay so for me
uh in my system the date is 29 December
as you can see
2023 and the tomorrow's date will be
December 2023 which I need to enter into
the text field okay so for this we are
going to use the date expression you can
see in the date expression we can
calculate uh using the base State uh
along with some deviations and also in a
uh defined format right so here uh if we
don't provide any base date it will take
today's date as the base date okay so
that's what I'm going to do and then
then I'm going to put a offset of + 1 D
and then I'm going to put a format here
okay uh which is uh in the format which
the obstacle is expecting the date to be
generated
okay so um here uh I'm going to put two
square brackets which means I'm putting
it empty I'm not providing any base date
so it will pick the default base date
which is today's date okay and then I'm
putting an offset of + 1D which means uh
it will calculate uh the offset as + one
uh and today's date
okay then uh the format so for this uh
we will give DD mm and then y y y
okay so this is the format which the
obstacle is expecting okay and this is
our data
expression now if you you want to check
whether this expression is correct or
not you can also right click and click
on translate
value and it should give you the correct
date okay so the expression is working
correctly it is generating the dynamic
date which is tomorrow State okay so now
uh I will change this to completed and
now we are going to run this uh in
scratchbook okay so as you can see it uh
enter tomor State and then um the
obstacle was completed obviously um it
did not detect that uh we have entered
the date so whenever this happens we
have already discussed you can always
use the send Keys uh expression to enter
any particular text into the text box
okay but this is how you can use the
dynamic date expression to generate any
uh dynamically generated date and then
you can use the offset to calculate uh
in terms of days months or years and
then you can also generate it uh on a
specific uh user defined format okay
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next video